Privacy Policy | Clevertype                      

top of page

* More

Use tab to navigate through the menu items.

CleverType by Pole Privacy Policy
=================================

This Privacy Policy provides privacy details on how we manage and protect your personal information for CleverType by Pole Keyboard products and services. This Privacy Policy is published pursuant to, and in compliance with the Information Technology Act, 2000, and the rules thereunder, more specifically the Information Technology (Reasonable Security Practices and Procedures and Sensitive Personal Data or Information) Rules, 2011, and the Information Technology Intermediaries Guidelines Rules 2011, and EU Data Protection directive framework as set forth by GDPR regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from the European Union member countries.

Please take a moment to familiarize yourself with our privacy practices and let us know if you have any questions. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH THE FOLLOWING PRIVACY POLICY, PLEASE DO NOT DOWNLOAD OR INSTALL THE CleverType KEYBOARD. IF YOU CONTINUE TO USE THE CleverType KEYBOARD, WE UNDERSTAND THAT YOU ARE AWARE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND ITS CONTENTS, AND HAVE PROVIDED YOUR “OPT-IN” CONSENT ON SUCH BASIS.

Our commitment to you
---------------------

This Privacy Policy explains how CleverType by Pole( hereinafter  “CleverType”, “we’, “us”, “our”) collect, use, disclose, process, share and protect any personal information that users (“User”, “you”, “your”) give us or that we collect from you, when you use CleverType Keyboard products and services. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using CleverType Keyboard products and services, it will only be used in accordance with this Privacy Policy and/or our terms and conditions for users.

Users may be subject to different protection standards and broader standards may therefore apply to some as per the compliance statement under this Privacy Policy. CleverType is committed to ensuring your privacy and the integrity of the data, and accordingly supplements the data protection requirements under law with additional good-practice modalities.

CleverType takes your privacy concerns very seriously, which is why it urges you to be careful with the information you share with others. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means (including offline) or from other sources. The use of information collected through the CleverType Keyboard or other CleverType products and services shall be limited to the purposes under this Privacy Policy.

The Privacy Policy is designed with you in mind, and it is important that you have a comprehensive understanding of our personal information collection and usage practices, while ensuring that ultimately, you have control of any personal information provided to CleverType. We consider your express and free consent for the aforementioned and below mentioned collection, storage and use of information and data by us, by virtue of your ‘opt-in’ consent provided for usage of the CleverType Keyboard.

We collect information for a lawful purpose connected with the CleverType Keyboard. Collection of such data and information is essential for the purpose of serving Users with the best version of our technologies and CleverType Keyboard.

Under this Privacy Policy, “personal information” or “personally identifiable information” means information that can be used to directly or indirectly identify an individual, either from that information alone or from that information combined with other information CleverType has access to about that individual, except as otherwise specifically provided by applicable laws in your region. We will use your personal information strictly in accordance with privacy policy.

Ultimately, what we want is the best for all our users. Should you have any concerns with our data handling practice as summarized in this Privacy Policy, please contact [support@clevertype.co](mailto:support@clevertype.co) to address your specific concerns. We will be happy to hear from you.

CONSENT AND BASIS FOR COLLECTION OF INFORMATION

By consenting to this Privacy Policy you are giving us permission to process your personal data specifically for the purposes identified. Acceptance of our services by downloading or using the CleverType Keyboard is an acceptance of the Privacy Policy

CleverType has a legal/lawful basis of collecting, processing and storage of personal data due to the following –

1. Upon your Consent – We may collect your data, personal information, and any other personally identifiable data after and only upon receiving your ‘opt-in’ consent on the CleverType Keyboard at various stages.
    
2. We collect information for the purpose of providing you services and improved deliverance through the CleverType Keyboard.
    
3. We will collect all requisite information for compliance with legal obligations; and
    
4. We might share information with whom we conduct business such as merchants, co-marketers, distributors, resellers, and other companies or organizations with whom CleverType enters into agreements to support its business and operations, for the purpose of analytics, feature based services and better deliverance of services.

What information is collected and how can we use it?

1\. What information is collected by us?

In order to provide our services to you, we may ask you to provide personal information that is necessary to provide those services to you. If you do not provide your personal information, we may not be able to provide you with our products or services or respond to your queries.

We may collect the following types of information (which may or may not be personal information), which is an inclusive list:

* Signing in to CleverType Keyboard: If you sign in to CleverType Keyboard with your Google Account, we ask permission to access your account info, such as your Google Account email or phone number, password, nickname, and profile photo. When you sign to CleverType Keyboard with your Facebook Account, we ask permission to access your account info, such as your Facebook id, nickname and email. When you sign to CleverType Keyboard with your MI Account, we ask permission to access your account info, such as your name, MI Account ID, profile photo When you’re not signed in to CleverType Keyboard, you can still use the basic functionality of CleverType Keyboard, such as emoji, typing, and updates. To provide such services, we collect information such as anonymous user ID assigned automatically and your purchases.
    
* Information you provide to us: we may collect all personal information you provide to us, like your email ID
    
* Information related to your application usage: including application basic information, such as keyboard settings (e.g. region, language).
    
* Log information: information related to your use of certain functions and apps. For example, IP addresses, crash information, input history, log information generated by using the services (such as registration time, access time, activity time, etc.).
    
* Information from third-party sources: When permitted by law, we will collect information about you from third-party sources. For example, we may obtain account IDs and nicknames from third-party social network services when signing up for CleverType keyboard.
    
* Non-personally identifiable information: We may also collect other types of information which are not directly or indirectly linked to an individual and which may not be defined as personal information according to applicable local laws. Such information may include statistical data generated when you use a specific service, such as anonymous ID, device type, system-related information, application version, network environment information, click events, application crash events, keyboard settings (e.g. country/region), input sentences, personal dictionary and application usage information. Such information is collected in order to improve the services we provide to you.

2\. How we use the personal information that we collect

The purpose of collecting personal information is to provide you with products and/or services, and to ensure that we comply with applicable laws, regulations and other regulatory requirements.

We may use your personal information for the following purposes:

* Providing, processing, maintaining, improving and developing our services for you, such as customer support.
    
* Handling your device, service or any general queries, such as answering customer inquiries, sending information about our events or notifications.
    
* Internal purposes such as data analysis, research and development of statistical information related to the use of our products and services to improve our products and services.
    
* Storing and maintaining information about you for our business operations or for fulfilling our legal obligations.
    
* Providing services locally on terminal devices that do not require communication with our servers, such as basic typing input, swiping input, clipboard, application debugging and performance logs.
    
* Other purposes with your consent.

How we share, transfer, and publicly disclose your personal information

We do not sell any personal information to third parties. To provide you with products and services described in this Privacy Policy, we may share your personal information with our third party service providers and business partners. CleverType will conduct due diligence and have contracts in place to ensure that third-party service providers comply with the applicable privacy laws in your jurisdiction. .

CleverType processes your personal information collected through CleverType keyboard for improving the accuracy of the input method and optimizing user experience.

Retention policy

​

Personal information will be held for as long as it is necessary to fulfill the purpose for which it was collected, or as required by applicable laws. We will cease to retain and delete or anonymize personal information once the purpose of collection is fulfilled, or after we confirm your request for erasure, or after we terminate the operation of the corresponding product or service. An exception to this is personal information that we are processing for public interest, scientific, historical research or statistical purposes. CleverType will continue to retain this type of information for longer than its standard retention period, where permitted based on applicable laws or your request, even if further data processing is not related to the original purpose of collection.

We store and process your personal information in data centers located in India and we do not transfer any personal information outside of the jurisdiction. If you are located in the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from Indian law, your acceptance to this policy is an affirmation and confirmation of your consent for us to collect and process your information in this manner.

Order of precedence

This Privacy Policy describes CleverType Keyboard products and services. In the event of inconsistency between CleverType Privacy Policy ([https://www.clevertype.co/privacy-policy),](https://www.clevertype.co/privacy-policy),) and this Privacy Policy, this Privacy Policy shall prevail. For the terms and conditions not stipulated in this Privacy Policy, CleverType Privacy Policy shall prevail.

Data Protection

​

All data stored in your device and transmitted to our cloud services from the CleverType Keyboard is encrypted with access restricted for the usage stated in this Privacy Policy.

HOW DO WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION?

As mentioned, we’re using technologies to secure and safeguard all information we collect, to the best of our capacity. We are concerned with protecting your data and privacy and take all requisite and reasonable steps for such protection, however, we cannot warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or guarantee that your information with may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, copied or destroyed by breach of any of our industrial standard physical, technical or managerial safeguards.

When you enter sensitive information on our registration forms, or other forms we encrypt the information in this data and send it to our servers through a secure connection for programmatic analysis to improve our language dictionaries. Data sent to our servers is archived when no longer required. No method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure, therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

We undertake reasonable security practices and procedures, security practices and procedures designed to protect such information from unauthorised access, damage, use, modification, disclosure or impairment.

If you have any queries about security on our website/app you can contact us at [support@clevertype.co](mailto:support@clevertype.co).

Rights of user

As per applicable data protection law, as supplemented by our internal practices, your principal rights as a User are:

* the right to access;
    
* the right to rectification;
    
* the right to erasure;
    
* the right to restrict processing;
    
* the right to object to processing;
    
* the right to data portability;
    
* the right to complain to a supervisory authority;
    
* the right to withdraw consent; and
    
* the right to be forgotten.

You have the right to request access to the information you have provided to us as you may deem fit. You can do this by contacting us on [support@clevertype.co](mailto:support@clevertype.co). We will ask you to verify your identity and provide you with requisite details. Once we receive your information and verifies the same satisfactorily and as per its procedure, we shall give you access to requisite personal information. While the Company shall make all due efforts to ensure solution of this concern, this procedure might take 72 hours or more.

If you believe that the information we have about you is incorrect, you can contact us to have the information updated and keep your data accurate.

If at any point you wish to have your information with us deleted, removed or forgotten from our database, you can contact us for the same at [support@clevertype.co](mailto:support@clevertype.co). We will take the necessary actions and step within 72 hours of the request being made.

You can opt-in or out of using CleverType as per your consent to the information being collected. If you wish to opt-out from tracking by CleverType, you can do so by sending a request at [support@clevertype.co](mailto:support@clevertype.co). We will process your request within seventy-two (72) business hours from receiving such a request.

An individual who is a current or former CleverType customer who seeks access or wishes to correct, amend or delete inaccurate data should direct his query to [support@clevertype.co](mailto:support@clevertype.co).

An individual who is a client of a current or former CleverType customer and who seeks access or wishes to correct, amend or delete inaccurate data should direct his/her query to the respective CleverType customer first and then, if no response is obtained or such response is not satisfactory to the individual, should contact at [support@clevertype.co](mailto:support@clevertype.co). If we receive a request under this provision, we will acknowledge it within seventy-two (72) business hours and handle it promptly.

​

What you can do

You can play your part in safeguarding your personal information by not disclosing your login password or account information to anybody unless such a person is duly authorized by you. We cannot be held responsible for lapses in security caused by third party access to your personal information as a result of your failure to keep your personal information private. Notwithstanding the foregoing, you must notify us immediately if there is any unauthorized use of your account by any other Internet user or any other breach of security.

Your assistance will help us protect the privacy of your personal information.

What happens if there is a change of control?

If we sell or otherwise transfer our products or our assets to another organization, data received from or about our Users may be among the items sold or transferred.

​

What control do I have over my data?

We take your consent at multiple stages throughout the CleverType Keyboard. You can discontinue use of the CleverType Keyboard at any point where you wish to not share further information with us.

MINORS

We consider it the responsibility of parents to monitor their children’s use of our services and apps. For a minor’s safety, we don’t allow usage of our services or the CleverType Keyboard or website without parental guidance.

We do not seek or intend to seek to receive any personal information from minors. Should a parent or guardian have reason to believe that a minor has provided us with personal information without their prior consent, please contact us to ensure that the personal information is removed and the minor unsubscribes from any of the applicable CleverType services.

GDPR COMPLIANCE STATEMENT

For EU users, we comply with the EU Data Protection directive framework as set forth by the EU regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from the European Union member countries. CleverType has certified that it adheres to the requirements of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access and enforcement. We will take upon the personal data breach, notifying the breach to relevant supervisory authority or under some circumstances, notifying the personal data breach to the data subjects by complying with applicable laws, including your local data protection legislation.

We respect and comply with the EU General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR); some of the key ways we comply with these regulations are:

* Detail of Information being collected - We have provided you with a list of information being collected from you by us.
    
* Consent - We have explained what you’re consenting to clearly and without ‘legalese’, and ask that you explicitly consent to provide us with any of your information before doing so.
    
* Breach Notification - In the event of a breach we will notify affected users within 72 hours of first having become aware of the breach.
    
* Right to Access - Users can request confirmation as to whether or not personal data concerning them is being processed, where and for what purpose. Further, we shall provide a copy of the personal data, free of charge, in an electronic format.
    
* Right to be Forgotten - Once we have compared your rights to "the public interest in the availability of the data", we may delete your personal data upon your written communication of such request to us on the abovementioned id within 72 hours of such request being made to us in the prescribed manner.
    
* Data Portability - We allow you to receive the personal data concerning you, which we will provide in a 'commonly used and machine readable format' within 72 hours of such request being made to us in the prescribed manner.
    
* Privacy by Design - We implement appropriate technical and organisational measures, in an effective way, in order to meet the requirements of this Regulation and protect the rights of users from whom data is collected. We hold and process only the data absolutely necessary for the completion of our duties (data minimisation), as well as limiting the access to personal data to those needing to act out the processing.
    
* What happens when we make changes to this policy?
    
* We keep our Privacy Policy under regular review and may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make material changes to our Privacy Policy, we will notify you by email (if you have provided your email address via your account) post the changes on the CleverType Keyboard, so that you may be aware of the information we collect and how we use it. We will not reduce your rights under this Privacy Policy without your explicit consent. Such changes to our Privacy Policy shall apply from the effective date as set out in the notice or on the CleverType Keyboard. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. Your continued use of our services and apps will be taken as acceptance of the updated Privacy Policy. We will seek your fresh consent before we collect more personal information from you or when we wish to use or disclose your personal information for new purposes.

​

RETURN AND REFUND

We are committed to ensuring the satisfaction and success of our customers with our services. This Return & Refund Policy outlines the terms regarding subscription purchases, cancellations, and refunds. Please review it carefully to understand your rights and obligations.

​

Subscription Purchase

Our platform offers various software subscription options tailored to meet different professional needs. When you subscribe to our service, you gain immediate access to our software tools and resources designed to help you achieve your goals. We encourage you to review the features and benefits of each subscription plan carefully before making a purchase. You have always option to cancel subscription after purchase

​

​

No Refund Policy  
Once a subscription is purchased, we do not offer refunds or credits for the subscription charges. We believe in providing our customers with the opportunity to explore the full capabilities of our software through detailed descriptions and, where possible, trial periods. This policy is in place because our service offers immediate access to extensive resources and proprietary content upon subscription. We encourage our customers to utilize the trial periods, where available, to ensure the service meets their needs before making a purchase.

​

​

Payment Issues

We understand that sometimes payment issues may arise, such as duplicate charges, incorrect billing amounts, or unauthorized transactions. In such cases, we are committed to rectifying any payment errors on our part. If you believe there has been a payment issue related to your subscription, please contact our customer service team immediately. We will review your claim, and if validated, we will issue a refund for the erroneous charge within a week.

For billing errors or unauthorized transactions, please provide us with the transaction details and any supporting documents to expedite the resolution process. The refund will be deposited back into your account within 7 days.  
  
Refunds for validated payment issues will be processed back to the original method of payment used during the subscription purchase.  
If you have any questions or concerns about our Return & Refund Policy, please do not hesitate to contact our customer support team. We are here to assist you with any inquiries or issues you may have regarding your subscription.

​

​

How can you contact us?

​

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy or any grievance in this respect, you may contact us at [support@clevertype.co](mailto:support@clevertype.co) or Any options in [Contact Us page](https://www.clevertype.co/contact-9). We understand how important your data is for you. We have attempted to answer all your questions. However, if you have questions or concerns regarding our Privacy Policy or practices, please [contact us](https://www.clevertype.co/contact-9) at [support@clevertype.co](mailto:support@clevertype.co) or +91 9526839791. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact immediately.

Thank you for taking the time to read our Privacy Policy!

​

​

​

CleverType Now!
---------------

© 2024 by CleverType

bottom of page
